A Guide to the Donald H. Harter papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA165
Rockefeller Archive Center
Donald H. Harter papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1963-1977, 1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harter, Donald H.
FA165
3.52 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Born in Breslau, Germany in 1933, Donald Harter came to the United States in 1940. He received his A.B. from the University of Pennsylvania in 1953 and a M.D. from Columbia University in 1957. Harter was a resident neurologist at the New York Neurological Institute until 1961 and was then a faculty member at Columbia's College of Physicians and Surgeons. He was a guest investigator at RU from 1963 to 1966. In 1975, Harter became the Charles L. Mix Professor and Chairman of the Department of Neurology at Northwestern University. He later became Senior Science Officer for the Howard Hughes Medical Institute.
Scope and Contents note
Consists primarily of laboratory notebooks, also reprints and a bibliography of publications. The laboratory notebooks cover the period that Dr. Harter was Guest Investigator at the Rockefeller Institute/Rockefeller University (1963-1966) and later a faculty member at the College of Physicians and Surgeons at Columbia University (1966-1975). Additional notebooks record his work during a sabbatical leave in the Department of Pathology at Cambridge University.
Arrangement note
Predominantly arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 H252
Conditions Governing Access note
Access to this collection is restricted pending permission from Rockefeller University.
Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Diseases; Neurosciences; Medical education; Pathology; Medical research; Rockefeller University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Reprints, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Reprints, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Curriculum Vitae and Publications List, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments I, 1963-1964; 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments I, 1964; 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments II, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments III, 1965-1969; 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments III, 1965-1967; 2 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments IV, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments V, 1965-1969; 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments V, 1967-1972; 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VI, 1972-1973; 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VI, 1973-1975; 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VII, 1964-1975; 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VII, 1965-1975; 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VIII, 1965-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments VIII, 1964-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments IX, 1967-1969; 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments IX, 1965-1972; 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments X, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XI, 1967-1972; 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XI, 1965-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XII, 1967-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XII, 1968-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XIII, 1967-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XIII, 1967-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XIV, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XV, 1972-1973; 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XV, 1972-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XVI, 1971-1973; 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XVI, 1972-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XVII, 1971; 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XVII, 1972-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XVIII, 1965-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XIX, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XX, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXI, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXII, 1965-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXIII, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXIV, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXV, 1972-1974; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXV, 1972-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXVI [sic], 1963-1965; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXVI [sic], 1964-1974; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXVI [sic], 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXVII, 1972-1975; 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments XXVII, 1968-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Notes, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Media (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - [untitled] (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - Experiments - Cambridge, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - Plating, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - Type Cultures I, 1965-1971; 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - Type Cultures I, 1966-1971; 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notebook - Type Cultures II, 1967-1977; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Laboratory Notebook - Type Cultures II, 1963-1973; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Laboratory Notebook - Sheep Choroid Plexus (SCP) I, 1964-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Laboratory Notebook - SCP I, 1965-1972; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Laboratory Notebook - SCP II, 1969-1971; 1 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebook - SCP II, 1972-1974; 2 of 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Laboratory Notebook - SCP II, 1967-1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)